<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<qti-assessment-item
    xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqtiasi_v3p0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqtiasi_v3p0 https://purl.imsglobal.org/spec/qti/v3p0/schema/xsd/imsqti_asiv3p0p1_v1p0.xsd http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML https://purl.imsglobal.org/spec/mathml/v3p0/schema/xsd/mathml3.xsd"
    identifier="medieval-revolts-evidence"
    title="Evidence for Medieval Revolts Claim"
    time-dependent="false"
    xml:lang="en-US">

    <qti-response-declaration base-type="identifier" cardinality="single" identifier="RESPONSE">
        <qti-correct-response>
            <qti-value>A</qti-value>
        </qti-correct-response>
    </qti-response-declaration>


    <qti-outcome-declaration identifier="SCORE" cardinality="single" base-type="float">
        <qti-default-value>
            <qti-value>0</qti-value>
        </qti-default-value>
    </qti-outcome-declaration>
    <qti-outcome-declaration identifier="FEEDBACK" cardinality="single" base-type="identifier"/>
    <qti-outcome-declaration identifier="FEEDBACK-INLINE" cardinality="single" base-type="identifier"/>

    <qti-item-body>
        <p>Before answering the question, read the following excerpt.</p>
        <div id="reference_text">
            <blockquote>
                <p>"In 1381, English peasants had their turn in a rebellion that spread through much of England and then to London, where King Richard II tricked and murdered its leaders. The other rebels were quickly dispersed and hunted down. Similar popular uprisings occurred - and were suppressed - in the Holy Roman Empire, Hungary, Norway, Finland, Sweden, Iberia and the Netherlands. Only one major revolt was successful. (...) Although most of these revolts were quickly put down, their message was not, it seems, entirely lost on the nobility. The English rebels had explicitly sought to end serfdom, and they had also questioned the social inequalities that were at the heart of aristocratic privilege. (...) These revolts, in other words, put the landed elite on notice, providing them with a good incentive to develop less exploitative methods of manorial management."</p>
                <p><small>From Judith M. Bennett and C. Warren Hollister, <em>Medieval Europe: A Short History</em> (New York: McGraw Hill, 2006), 331-332.</small></p>
            </blockquote>
        </div>
        
        <qti-choice-interaction response-identifier="RESPONSE" shuffle="true" max-choices="1">
            <qti-prompt>What type of evidence would support this claim?</qti-prompt>
            <qti-simple-choice identifier="A">
                Changes in laws regarding the rights of peasants after revolts were suppressed
                <qti-feedback-inline outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK-INLINE" identifier="A">This is the best answer. Changes in laws would indicate a change in thinking about peasants' rights and roles. It would represent an effort to prevent future conflict.</qti-feedback-inline>
            </qti-simple-choice>
            <qti-simple-choice identifier="B">
                Laws remaining the same after revolts were suppressed
                <qti-feedback-inline outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK-INLINE" identifier="B">No change in the laws would indicate a lack of concern about further conflict being caused by the current situation.</qti-feedback-inline>
            </qti-simple-choice>
            <qti-simple-choice identifier="C">
                Records showing that more popular uprisings won military victories
                <qti-feedback-inline outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK-INLINE" identifier="C">The claim is that revolts could lead to change regardless of whether they won military victory.</qti-feedback-inline>
            </qti-simple-choice>
            <qti-simple-choice identifier="D">
                Peasants gaining political offices
                <qti-feedback-inline outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK-INLINE" identifier="D">Even if changes were made, peasants were not typically allowed to hold important political offices due to the social hierarchies that existed.</qti-feedback-inline>
            </qti-simple-choice>
        </qti-choice-interaction>

        <qti-feedback-block outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK" identifier="CORRECT" show-hide="show">
            <qti-content-body>
                <p><strong>Correct!</strong> The author claims that even though the revolts were militarily defeated, the ruling class heard the "message" and had an "incentive to develop less exploitative methods." Evidence of new laws improving the rights or conditions for peasants would directly support this claim.</p>
            </qti-content-body>
        </qti-feedback-block>
        <qti-feedback-block outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK" identifier="INCORRECT" show-hide="show">
            <qti-content-body>
                <p><strong>Not quite.</strong> The author's central claim is that the revolts, despite failing, successfully frightened the nobility into making changes. To support this, you need to find evidence that shows a positive change for peasants <em>after</em> the failed revolts.</p>
            </qti-content-body>
        </qti-feedback-block>
    </qti-item-body>

    <qti-response-processing>
        <qti-response-condition>
            <qti-response-if>
                <qti-match>
                    <qti-variable identifier="RESPONSE"/>
                    <qti-correct identifier="RESPONSE"/>
                </qti-match>
                <qti-set-outcome-value identifier="SCORE">
                    <qti-base-value base-type="float">1</qti-base-value>
                </qti-set-outcome-value>
                <qti-set-outcome-value identifier="FEEDBACK">
                    <qti-base-value base-type="identifier">CORRECT</qti-base-value>
                </qti-set-outcome-value>
            </qti-response-if>
            <qti-response-else>
                <qti-set-outcome-value identifier="SCORE">
                    <qti-base-value base-type="float">0</qti-base-value>
                </qti-set-outcome-value>
                <qti-set-outcome-value identifier="FEEDBACK">
                    <qti-base-value base-type="identifier">INCORRECT</qti-base-value>
                </qti-set-outcome-value>
            </qti-response-else>
        </qti-response-condition>
    </qti-response-processing>

</qti-assessment-item>
